smude.edu.in 2010-11-22

# Privacy Policy | Sikkim Manipal University-Distance Education | Privacy Policy Summary | MBA Distance Learning

**Privacy Policy Summary**   
Thank you for visiting the Sikkim Manipal University - Directorate of Distance Education (SMU-DE) website and reviewing our privacy policy. Our policy is simple: We collect no personal information about you unless you choose to provide that information to us. We do not give, share, sell, or transfer any personal information to a third party. The images used on the website are representative only. If you want to know more about how we record non-personal information about your visit or how we use information that you voluntarily submit, read on. 

**Non-personal Information We Record**   
We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site by identifying (1) which parts of our site are most heavily used, and (2) which portion of our audience comes from within the SMU-DE network.   
If you do nothing during your visit but browse through the website, read pages, or download information, our website's operating system will automatically record some general information about your visit.   
During your visit, our web operating system will record: 

  * The **Internet domain** for your Internet service, such as "xyz.com" or "xyz.net" if you use a private Internet access account or "yourcollege.edu" if you connect from a college or university domain. 

  * The **type of browser** (such as "Netscape version X" or "Internet Explorer version X") that you are using. 

  * The **type of operating system** that you use (such as Macintosh, UNIX, or Windows). 

  * The **date and time** you visit our site, and the **web pages that you visit** on our site. 

  * The address of the **previous website** you were visiting, if you linked to us from another website. 

We use this information for statistical analysis, to help us make our site more useful to visitors. This tracking system does not record information about individuals. 

**Cookies**   
On certain SMU-DE web pages, we use "cookies" to help you use our websites interactively. A cookie is a small file that a website transfers to your computer's hard disk, usually to keep track of you while you are connected to that site. The cookies on SMU-DE web pages do not collect information about you, but only about your browser "session." The cookie makes it easier for you to use the dynamic features of these web pages, without having to provide the same information again as you move from one page to another. To protect your privacy, be sure to close your browser completely after you have finished conducting business with a website that uses cookies. If you are concerned about the potential use of information gathered from your computer by cookies, you can set your browser to prompt you before it accepts a cookie. Most Internet browsers have settings that let you identify and/or reject cookies. 

**Information from Email You Send to Us**   
If you decide to send us an electronic mail message (e-mail), the message will usually contain your return e-mail address. If you include personally-identifying information in your e-mail because you want us to address issues specific to your situation, we may use that information in responding to your request. Also, e-mail is not necessarily secure against interception. Please send only information necessary to help us process your request. 

**Information Collected from Interactive Forms  
**On some of our web pages we offer interactive forms that let you voluntarily submit personal information (such as your e-mail address, name, or organisation). This occurs when you are registering for online counseling, various tests, quizzes, seminars, workshops, training sessions offered by SMU-DE, downloading admission forms from SMU-DE and so on. In those cases, all submitted information is used only for the purposes for which it is intended and is not made available to any third party or sold to any outside organisation for its use in marketing or solicitation without your consent. 

**Links to Other Sites  
**Our policy discloses the privacy practices for the SMU-DE website. But SMU-DE provides links to other websites. When you leave the SMU-DE website (www.smude.edu.in), you will be going to sites that are beyond our control. These other sites may send their own cookies to users, collect data, or solicit personal information. The privacy policies and procedures described here for SMU-DE do not apply to any external links. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of any site you link to from ours, especially if you share any personal information. Be informed. You are the person best qualified to protect your own privacy. 

**Security  
**This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. 

**Changes to this Policy  
**An announcement of any changes to this policy will be posted prominently on the first page of our web site for three months before any changes go into effect. 

**Effective Date**   
The effective date of this policy was 26-Jan-2010.
